let questions=
[
    {
    "question": "1- What is the main function of the Attitude Determination and Control System (ADCS) of a satellite?",
   "answer": "B) Controlling the orbit and attitude of the satellite",
    "options": [
    "A) Monitoring the status of sensors and subsystems", 
   "B) Controlling the orbit and attitude of the satellite", 
   "C) Switching on and off the communication system", 
   "D) Providing information on range and angles of the satellite"]
    },
    {
    "question": "2- Which statement regarding the telemetry system is correct?", 
   "answer": "B) It sends data derived from sensors on the satellite to the controlling earth station.", 
   " options": [ 
   "A) It controls the orbit and attitude of the satellite.", 
   "B) It sends data derived from sensors on the satellite to the controlling earth station.", 
   "C) It operates switches on the satellite.", 
   "D) It provides information on the range and angles of the satellite. "
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "3- What role does the tracking system play in satellite operation?", 
   "answer": "C) Providing information on the range and angles of the satellite", 
   "options": [
    "A) Controlling the orbit and attitude of the satellite",
    "B) Monitoring the status of sensors and subsystems", 
   "C) Providing information on the range and angles of the satellite", 
   "D) Switching on and off the communication system"
   ]
   }, 
   {
    "question": "4- Which statement is true about communication satellites?", 
   "answer": "D) They derive electrical power from solar cells.",
   "options": [ 
   "A) They derive electrical power from batteries.", 
   "B) They are stabilized by momentum wheels.", 
   "C) They are owned and operated by the controlling earth station.", 
   "D) They derive electrical power from solar cells."
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "5- What is the purpose of solar cells on communication satellites?", 
   "answer": "C) To convert incident sunlight into electrical energy", 
   "options": [ 
   "A) To power the subsystems during launch", 
   "B) To provide information on the range and angles of the satellite", 
   "C) To convert incident sunlight into electrical energy", 
   "D) To control the orbit and attitude of the satellite"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "6- How are large GEO satellites typically stabilized?",
   "answer": "B) By 3-axis stabilization", 
    "options": [ 
   "A) By spin stabilization", 
   "B) By 3-axis stabilization", 
   "C) By momentum wheels", 
   "D) By flat panel rotation"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "7- What is a characteristic of spin-stabilized satellites?", 
   "answer": "A) They have cylindrical bodies covered in solar cells.", 
   "options": [ 
   "A) They have cylindrical bodies covered in solar cells.", 
   "B) They derive electrical power from batteries.", 
   "C) They are controlled by the telemetry system.", 
   "D) They can repoint individual antennas. "
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "8- Why must the satellite carry batteries?", 
   "answer": "C) To power the subsystems during launch and night", 
   "options": [ 
   "A) To convert sunlight into electrical energy", 
   "B) To control the orbit and attitude of the satellite", 
   "C) To power the subsystems during launch and night", 
   "D) To switch on and off the communication system"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "9- What condition(s) must be satisfied for an orbit to be classified as geostationary?", 
   "answer": "D) All of the above",
   "options": [ 
   "A) The orbit must be circular.", 
   "B) The inclination of the orbit must be zero.", 
   "C) The altitude must be 36,000 km.", 
   "D) All of the above"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "10- What distinguishes a geostationary orbit from a geosynchronous orbit?", 
   "answer": "B) Period of rotation", 
   "options": [ 
   "A) Altitude", 
   "B) Period of rotation", 
   "C) Inclination", 
   "D) None of the above"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
   "question": "11- What is the primary purpose of a polar orbit?", 
   "answer": "B) Weather forecasting", 
   "options": [
   "A) Domestic communication", 
   "B) Weather forecasting", 
   "C) GPS navigation", 
   "D) Television broadcasting"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "12- Which orbit is used for search and rescue satellite-aided tracking (SARSAT)?", 
   "answer": "C) Polar orbit", 
   "options": [
   "A) Geostationary orbit", 
   "B) Sun-synchronous orbit", 
   "C) Polar orbit", 
   "D) Inclined orbit"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "13- What distinguishes a prograde orbit from a retrograde orbit?", 
   "answer": "C) Direction of satellite's movement", 
   "options": [
   "A) Altitude", 
   "B) Inclination", 
   "C) Direction of satellite's movement", 
   "D) None of the above"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "14- What is the key characteristic of a Sun-synchronous orbit?", 
   "answer": "A) It passes over any given point of the planet's surface at the same local mean solar time.", 
   "options": [
   "A) It passes over any given point of the planet's surface at the same local mean solar time.", 
   "B) It maintains a constant altitude.", 
   "C) It has a circular shape.", 
   "D) It is located above the equator. "
   ] 
   }, 
   {
    "question": "15- What is one of the primary advantages of a Sun-synchronous orbit?", 
   "answer": "A) Continuous sunlight for solar panels", 
   "options": [ 
   "A) Continuous sunlight for solar panels", 
   "B) Faster communication speed", 
   "C) Higher altitude for better coverage", 
   "D) Lower cost of deployment"
   ] 
   }, 
   {
   "question": "16- Which type of satellite orbit is commonly used for imaging, spy, and weather satellites?",
   "answer": "D) Sun-synchronous orbit",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Geostationary orbit", 
   "B) Polar orbit", 
   "C) Inclined orbit", 
   "D) Sun-synchronous orbit",
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "17- What is the typical distance of Low Earth Orbit (LEO) satellites from the Earth's surface? ",
   "answer": "A) Around 1,000 km",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Around 1,000 km", 
   "B) Around 8,000 km", 
   "C) Around 36,000 km", 
   "D) Around 100,000 km"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "18- What has historically been the primary use of Mid Earth Orbit (MEO) satellites? ",
   "answer": "C) GPS and navigation applications",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Science and imaging ",
   "B) Low-bandwidth telecommunications", 
   "C) GPS and navigation applications", 
   "D) High-bandwidth data connectivity"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "19- What is the primary purpose of High-Throughput Satellite (HTS) MEO constellations? ",
   "answer": "A) Low-latency, high-bandwidth data connectivity",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Low-latency, high-bandwidth data connectivity", 
   "B) Low-bandwidth telecommunications", 
   "C) Imaging and science applications", 
   "D) GPS and navigation applications"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "20- Which type of satellite orbit is densely populated with thousands of satellites primarily addressing science, imaging, and low-bandwidth telecommunications needs? ",
   "answer": "A) Low Earth Orbit (LEO)",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Low Earth Orbit (LEO) ",
   "B) Mid-Earth Orbit (MEO) ", 
   "C) Geostationary Orbit (GEO) ", 
   "D) Polar Orbit"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "21- What is the next generation of HTS LEO satellites intended to serve? ",
   "answer": "C) Communication markets such as mass-consumer and enterprise broadband internet",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Science and imaging markets", 
   "B) GPS and navigation markets", 
   "C) Communication markets such as mass-consumer and enterprise broadband internet", 
   "D) Low-bandwidth telecommunications needs"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "22- What do classical (Keplerian) orbital elements directly represent? ",
   "answer": "B) Orbit shape, size, and orientation",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Orbital eccentricity", 
   "B) Orbit shape, size, and orientation", 
   "C) Orbital period", 
   "D) Orbital inclination"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "23- According to Kepler's 1st Law, what shape is the orbit of each planet? ",
   "answer": "B) Ellipse",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Parabola", 
   "B) Ellipse", 
   "C) Circle", 
   "D) Hyperbola"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "24- What is the significance of cutting a cone with a plane at different angles in understanding orbits?",
   "answer": "C) It reveals the shapes of orbits, known as conic sections.",
   "options": [ 
   "A) It helps determine the eccentricity of the orbit. ", 
   "B) It provides insights into the orbit's orientation. ", 
   "C) It reveals the shapes of orbits, known as conic sections. ", 
   "D) It demonstrates the variability of orbital periods"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "25- Which type of orbit has an eccentricity of 0? ",
   "answer": "A) Circular orbit",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Circular orbit", 
   "B) Elliptical orbit", 
   "C) Parabolic orbit", 
   "D) Hyperbolic orbit"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "26- What does a parabolic orbit with eccentricity e=1e=1 suggest about the object's origin?",
   "answer": "C) It is interstellar in origin.",
   "options": [ 
   "A) It originates from the Oort cloud.", 
   "B) It is in a geostationary orbit.", 
   "C) It is interstellar in origin.", 
   "D) It has a stable orbit around the Sun."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "27- What is the significance of a geostationary orbit with an inclination of 0 degrees?",
   "answer": "A) The spacecraft remains stationary over a specific location on Earth's equator.",
   "options": [ 
   "A) The spacecraft remains stationary over a specific location on Earth's equator. ", 
   "B) The orbit has a highly elliptical shape. ", 
   "C) The spacecraft orbits Earth at a high speed. ", 
   "D) The orbit has a period of 24 hours. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "28- For what purpose are geostationary orbits primarily used? ",
   "answer": "B) Communication satellites and weather satellites",
   "options": [ 
   "A) Science missions. ", 
   "B) Communication satellites and weather satellites. ", 
   "C) Observing distant galaxies. ", 
   "D) Monitoring polar ice caps. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "29- Which type of orbit is associated with the International Space Station (ISS)?",
   "answer": "C) Circular orbit",
   " options ": [
   "A) Elliptical orbit",
   "B) Geostationary orbit",
   "C) Circular orbit",
   "D) Hyperbolic orbit"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "30- What is the primary reason for performing orbital maneuvers after a satellite's initial launch?",
   "answer": "B) To achieve the desired final orbit",
   "options": [
   "A) To minimize the satellite's weight",
   "B) To achieve the desired final orbit",
   "C) To increase the satellite's speed",
   "D) To reduce the satellite's communication latency"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "31- Which of the following is a characteristic of single-impulse orbit adjustment?",
   "answer": "C) It is commonly used to circularize elliptic orbits.",
   "options": [
   "A) It requires multiple thrust impulses.",
   "B) It always results in a change in the satellite's argument of perigee.",
   "C) It is commonly used to circularize elliptic orbits.",
   "D) It is primarily used to maintain the altitude of low-orbit satellites."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "32- What is a principal characteristic of single-impulse orbital adjustment?",
   "answer": "A) The initial and final orbits will always have at least one common point.",
   "options": [
   "A) The initial and final orbits will always have at least one common point.",
   "B) The initial and final orbits will never intersect.",
   "C) Single-impulse adjustments require less fuel than multiple-thrust adjustments.",
   "D) Single-impulse adjustments result in significant changes to the satellite's orbit."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "33- What was the original purpose of the Hohmann transfer between orbits?",
   "answer": "A) To allow a transfer between two circular orbits with minimum fuel consumption",
   "options": [
   "A) To allow a transfer between two circular orbits with minimum fuel consumption",
   "B) To maximize the satellite's altitude",
   "C) To achieve the highest possible satellite speed",
   "D) To minimize the satellite's orbital period"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "34- What is a requirement for the intermediate transfer orbit (TO) in a Hohmann transfer?",
   "answer": "A) Its perigee radius vector must equal the radius of the target orbit.",
   "options": [
   "A) Its perigee radius vector must equal the radius of the target orbit.",
   "B) Its apogee radius vector must equal the radius of the initial orbit.",
   "C) Its eccentricity must be greater than 1.",
   "D) Its inclination must be 0 degrees."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "35- What is the primary difference between a Hohmann transfer and a Bi-Elliptical transfer?",
   "answer": "A) The number of transfer orbits involved",
   "options": [
   "A) The number of transfer orbits involved",
   "B) The speed of the satellite during the transfer",
   "C) The fuel consumption required for the transfer",
   "D) The shape of the resulting orbit after the transfer"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "36- What is the ground track of a satellite?",
   "answer": "B) The trace of sub-points over time",
   "options": [
   "A) The altitude of the satellite above Earth's surface",
   "B) The trace of sub-points over time",
   "C) The latitude at which the satellite is located",
   "D) The great circle formed by the bisection of the Earth with the orbital plane of the satellite"
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "37- How does the Earth's rotation affect the ground track of a satellite?",
   "answer": "C) It causes the ground track to shift towards the west.",
   "options": [
   "A) It causes the ground track to shift towards the east.",
   "B) It has no effect on the ground track.",
   "C) It causes the ground track to shift towards the west.",
   "D) It changes the altitude of the satellite."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "38- What effect does altitude have on the ground track of a satellite?",
   "answer": "A) Higher altitude leads to a smaller displacement of the ground track towards the west.",
   "options": [
   "A) Higher altitude leads to a smaller displacement of the ground track towards the west.",
   "B) Higher altitude leads to a greater displacement of the ground track towards the east.",
   "C) Higher altitude leads to a larger angular velocity of the satellite.",
   "D) Higher altitude leads to a smaller angular velocity of the satellite."
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "39- How does latitude affect the shift in the ground track of a satellite? ",
   "answer": " C) The shift in the ground track is zero at the poles.",
   "options": [
   "A) The shift in the ground track is zero at the equator. ", 
   "B) The shift in the ground track increases with increasing latitude. ", 
   "C) The shift in the ground track is zero at the poles. ", 
   "D) The shift in the ground track is greater at lower latitudes. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "40- What is nodal regression in satellite orbits caused by? ",
   "answer": "B) The Earth's oblate nature. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The Earth's rotation. ", 
   "B) The Earth's oblate nature. ", 
   "C) The altitude of the satellite. ", 
   "D) The eccentricity of the orbit. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "41- How does the inclination of the orbit affect the ground track of a satellite?",
   "answer": "B) It determines the maximum latitude the ground track will reach. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) It determines the maximum altitude of the ground track. ", 
   "B) It determines the maximum latitude the ground track will reach. ", 
   "C) It causes the ground track to become circular. ", 
   "D) It has no effect on the ground track. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "42- What are perturbations in satellite motion? ",
   "answer": "B) Disturbances in the regular motion of a celestial body. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Changes in the satellite's altitude. ", 
   "B) Disturbances in the regular motion of a celestial body. ", 
   "C) Changes in the satellite's inclination. ", 
   "D) Alterations in the satellite's orbital period. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "43- Which type of perturbation is caused by the Earth's asymmetrical mass? ",
   "answer": "B) Gravitational. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Atmospheric drag. ", 
   "B) Gravitational. ", 
   "C) Solar wind/radiation pressure. ", 
   "D) Electromagnetic. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "44- What effect does atmospheric drag have on a satellite?",
   "answer": "C) It reduces the satellite's energy. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) It increases the satellite's altitude. ", 
   "B) It changes the satellite's inclination. ", 
   "C) It reduces the satellite's energy. ", 
   "D) It stabilizes the satellite's orbit. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "45- What are stable points in Earth's gravitational field? ",
   "answer": "C) 75E and 105W. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Himalayas and Rocky Mountains. ", 
   "B) Marshall Islands and Portugal. ", 
   "C) 75E and 105W. ", 
   "D) 165E and 5W. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "46- What effect does solar wind/radiation pressure have on a satellite? ",
   "answer": "B) It reduces the satellite's energy. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) It changes the satellite's altitude. ",
   "B) It reduces the satellite's energy. ", 
   "C) It increases the satellite's angular velocity. ", 
   "D) It stabilizes the satellite's orbit. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "47- What is the Doppler shift in satellite communication?",
   "answer": "A) The variation in frequency of the satellite transmitter with respect to the receiver. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The variation in frequency of the satellite transmitter with respect to the receiver. ", 
   "B) The change in the satellite's altitude. ", 
   "C) The effect of solar eclipses on satellite operations. ", 
   "D) The variation in the satellite's orbital period. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "48- When does a solar eclipse occur for a satellite?",
   "answer": "A) When the satellite's solar panels fail to receive sunlight due to an obstruction from a celestial body. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) When the satellite's solar panels fail to receive sunlight due to an obstruction from a celestial body. ", 
   "B) When the satellite passes directly between the Earth and the Sun. ", 
   "C) When the satellite's orbit intersects with the Moon's orbit. ", 
   "D) When the satellite's altitude decreases suddenly. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "49- What is Sun transit outrage?",
   "answer": "C) The temporary loss of communication due to the satellite passing directly between the Sun and Earth. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The temporary shift of satellite traffic to other satellites during a solar eclipse. ", 
   "B) The variation in the satellite's orbital period due to solar radiation. ", 
   "C) The temporary loss of communication due to the satellite passing directly between the Sun and Earth. ", 
   "D) The effect of solar wind on satellite operations. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "50- What are launch windows in the context of satellite launches? ",
   "answer": "B) The period of time during which a satellite can be launched directly into a specific orbital plane from a specific launch site. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The time period during which a satellite can be launched from any launch site. ", 
   "B) The period of time during which a satellite can be launched directly into a specific orbital plane from a specific launch site. ", 
   "C) The duration of time required for a satellite to reach its desired orbit. ", 
   "D) The time interval during which a satellite's telemetry data is collected. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "51- How many launch opportunities are available per day if the latitude of the launch site is less than the orbit's inclination? ",
   "answer": "B) Two per day. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) One per day. ", 
   "B) Two per day. ", 
   "C) None. ", 
   "D) It depends on the fuel requirements. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "52- What is the result of launching a satellite at an azimuth of 90 degrees?",
   "answer": "A) The satellite will have a lower inclination. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The satellite will have a lower inclination. ", 
   "B) The satellite will have a greater inclination. ", 
   "C) The satellite will be placed directly into a geostationary orbit. ",
   "D) The launch will not be successful. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "53- What is the purpose of the apogee maneuver in the launch sequence?", 
   "answer": "C) To circularize the orbit at the geostationary altitude. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) To correct the orbit for its inclination. ", 
   "B) To place the satellite in a transfer orbit. ", 
   "C) To circularize the orbit at the geostationary altitude. ", 
   "D) To correct the satellite's attitude. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "54- What are the two main functions of the attitude and orbit control subsystem? ", 
   "answer": "C) Controlling the satellite's orbital path and attitude. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Controlling the satellite's weight and size. ", 
   "B) Controlling the satellite's velocity and altitude. ", 
   "C) Controlling the satellite's orbital path and attitude. ", 
   "D) Controlling the satellite's communication systems and power supply. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "55- What does the attitude of a satellite refer to? ", 
   "answer": "C) The satellite's orientation determined by its axes. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The satellite's altitude above the Earth's surface. ", 
   "B) The satellite's distance from the launch site. ", 
   "C) The satellite's orientation determined by its axes. ", 
   "D) The satellite's speed relative to other objects in space. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "56- What are the two common types of attitude control systems mentioned in the passage? ", 
   "answer": "D) Spin stabilization and three-axis stabilization. ",
   "options": [
   "A) Spin stabilization and gravity gradient boom. ", 
   "B) Thrusters and boosters. ", 
   "C) Solar panels and antennas. ", 
   "D) Spin stabilization and three-axis stabilization. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "57- What is the purpose of spin-stabilized satellites during the launch phase? ", 
   "answer": "C) To correct pitch using the de-spun antenna system. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) To maintain communication with the ground station. ", 
   "B) To control the satellite's velocity. ", 
   "C) To correct pitch using the de-spun antenna system. ", 
   "D) To provide small orbital corrections using boosters. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "58- How do active attitude control systems differ from passive systems? ", 
   "answer": "A) Active systems use sensors to make corrections based on measurements, while passive systems achieve equilibrium at the desired orientation. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Active systems use sensors to make corrections based on measurements, while passive systems achieve equilibrium at the desired orientation. ", 
   "B) Active systems use mechanical components for stabilization, while passive systems rely on external forces. ", 
   "C) Active systems require less power, while passive systems are more reliable. ", 
   "D) Active systems are only used during the launch phase, while passive systems operate during the satellite's orbit. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "59- Which sensors are used to determine the satellite's position with respect to reference directions? ", 
   "answer": "B) Earth sensors and sun/star sensors. ",
   "options": [
   "A) Velocity sensors. ", 
   "B) Earth sensors and sun/star sensors. ",
   "C) Temperature sensors. ", 
   "D) Pressure sensors. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "60- What generates the correction torque in the attitude control system? ", 
   "answer": "B) The difference between the current and desired attitudes. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) The satellite's velocity vector. ",
   "B) The difference between the current and desired attitudes. ", 
   "C) The altitude of the satellite. ", 
   "D) The number of rocket stages used in the launch. "
   ]
   }, 
   {
   "question": "61- What is the purpose of the orbit control subsystem? ", 
   "answer": "C) To compensate for perturbation forces. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) To monitor satellite health. ", 
   "B) To collect telemetry data. ", 
   "C) To compensate for perturbation forces. ", 
   "D) To track the satellite's position. "]
   },
   {
   "question": "62- How often are station-keeping maneuvers conducted for geostationary satellites? ",
   "answer": "C) Every two weeks. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Every day. ", 
   "B) Every month. ", 
   "C) Every two weeks. ", 
   "D) Every year. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "63- Which type of orbit corrections require more fuel? ",
   "answer": "B) North-south corrections. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) East-west corrections. ", 
   "B) North-south corrections. ", 
   "C) Tangential corrections. ", 
   "D) Radial corrections. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "64- What type of satellites utilize radial jets for corrections? ",
   "answer": "A) Three-axis stabilized satellites. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Three-axis stabilized satellites. ", 
   "B) Spin-stabilized satellites. ", 
   "C) Geostationary satellites. ", 
   "D) Low Earth orbit satellites. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "65- What is the responsibility of the tracking component of the TT&C subsystem?",
   "answer": "B) Determining satellite position and travel. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Monitoring subsystem health. ", 
   "B) Determining satellite position and travel. ", 
   "C) Executing remote control commands. ", 
   "D) Transmitting telemetry data to Earth stations. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "66- What is the primary function of telemetry in the TT&C subsystem? ",
   "answer": "B) Monitoring satellite health. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Executing control commands. ", 
   "B) Monitoring satellite health. ", 
   "C) Determining orbital parameters. ", 
   "D) Transmitting data from various sensors. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "67- What role does the command element play in the TT&C subsystem?",
   "answer": "D) Receiving and executing remote control commands. ",
   "options": [
   "A) Determining satellite position. ", 
   "B) Collecting telemetry data. ", 
   "C) Transmitting data to Earth stations. ",
   "D) Receiving and executing remote control commands. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "68- What is the main function of the Attitude Determination and Control Subsystem (ADCS)? ",
   "answer": "C) Stabilizing and orienting the vehicle. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Transmitting data to the ground station. ", 
   "B) Generating electrical power for the spacecraft. ", 
   "C) Stabilizing and orienting the vehicle. ", 
   "D) Analyzing atmospheric conditions. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "69- Which component of the ADCS senses the orientation of the spacecraft relative to reference points? ",
   "answer": "C) Sensors. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Actuators. ", 
   "B) Thrusters. ", 
   "C) Sensors. ", 
   "D) Solar arrays. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "70- What is the purpose of spin stabilization? ",
   "answer": "B) To rotate the spacecraft about a vertical axis. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) To actively stabilize all three axes. ", 
   "B) To rotate the spacecraft about a vertical axis. ", 
   "C) To provide gyroscopic stability to the lower section. ", 
   "D) To reduce the complexity of the ADCS. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "71- Which theorem allows the calculation of the moment of inertia around any axis from the moment of inertia around a parallel axis passing through the center of mass? ",
   "answer": "A) Parallel-axis theorem. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Parallel-axis theorem. ", 
   "B) Angular momentum theorem. ", 
   "C) Kepler's theorem. ", 
   "D) Inertia theorem. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "72- What is an advantage of 3-axis stabilization over spin stabilization? ",
   "answer": "C) Higher accuracy in pointing. ", 
   "options": [
   "A) Reduced complexity. ", 
   "B) Lower mass. ", 
   "C) Higher accuracy in pointing. ", 
   "D) Simpler payload integration. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "73- What type of sensor detects the boundary between deep space and the upper atmosphere using infrared technology? ",
   "answer": "b) Earth Sensor (horizon sensor). ", 
   "options": [
   "a) Sun Sensor. ", 
   "b) Earth Sensor (horizon sensor). ", 
   "c) Star Sensor. ", 
   "d) Scanner. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "74- Which type of sensor is used for spinning spacecraft or on a rotating mount? ",
   "answer": "d) Scanner. ",
   "options": [
   "a) Sun Sensor. ", 
   "b) Star Sensor. " ,
   "c) Tracker/Mapper. ",
   "d) Scanner. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "75- What is the main function of the Inertial Measurement Unit (IMU)? ",
   "answer": "b) Measuring the rate of rotation of the spacecraft. ", 
   "options": [
   "a) Detecting the boundary between deep space and the upper atmosphere. ", 
   "b) Measuring the rate of rotation of the spacecraft. ", 
   "c) Observing the position of celestial bodies. ", 
   "d) Analyzing the magnetic field of the Earth. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "76- Which type of actuator requires a magnetic field model stored in the computer? ",
   "answer": "c) Magnetometer. ", 
   "options": [
   "a) Gravity Gradient Booms. ", 
   "b) Dampers. ", 
   "c) Magnetometer. ", 
   "d) Torque Rods. "
   ]
   },
   {
   "question": "77- What type of actuator is used for actively controlling the orientation of the spacecraft? ",
   "answer": "b) Thrusters. ", 
   "options": [
   "a) Passive. ", 
   "b) Thrusters. ", 
   "c) Wheels. ", 
   "d) Gyros. "
   ]
   }
   ]